American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to W[illia]m D. Lewis and Fred[eric]k Fraley, November 5, 1841; 7 7/8" x 10"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Messrs. Lewis and Fraley to act as appraisers for valuing property on 5th. street near Chestnut.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1841; 10x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britian and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end.and add.: William Vaughan. Thanks for the Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, November 13, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bowditch, Henry I. (Henry Ingersoll), 1808-1892
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: a pamphlet from the Numismatic Society of Lonson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 16, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Geo[rge] Campbell, Sec. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., November 16, 1841; 8 1/8" x 10 1/4"; Muséum national d'histoire naturelle (France)
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. (In French.) Acknowledging receipt of designated volumes of Transactions and Proceedings of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 18, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter from Mr. [J. G.] Schwartz. Discussion of the Chinese system of writing. FILM 403 FRAME 161
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 18, 1841; 9-3/4x8; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thaddeus Mason Harris. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Nagy's letter in relation to experiments with the pendulum, Nov. 19, 1841; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: A. D. Bache and R. M. Patterson. 2p., end. See APS Proceedings, II, 118.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 19, 1841; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisele. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Account with the American philosophical society, Nov. 26, 1841; 8x7; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    A.D.S. 1p.,end.and end.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, Secretary of A.P.S., November 26, 1841; 8" x 10"; Markoe, Francis, 1801-1871
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. The secretary of the National Institution acknowledges receipt of letter of August 20, and package from A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 27, 1841; 9x7; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    L.S.: W.A. Graham. 1p.,end.and add.: By favour of P.Vaughan, Eqr. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Petty Vaughan,for the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 29, 1841; 12-3/4x8-1/4; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edmund R. Daniell. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 30, 1841; 8" x 10"; Penrose, Charles B. (Charles Bingham), 1862-1925
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Forwards Vaughan a copy of the State of Commerce. Census for 1840 not yet completed.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan, Dec. 1, 1841; 2x8; Ewing, J. O.
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 2, 1841; 15x9; Geological Society of London
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 3, 1841; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for payment for mounting a geological map, Dec. 7, 1841; 3x8; Barnes, Rufus L.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 9, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Librarian of A.P.S., Princeton, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for note which informed him "of the arrival of a number of interesting scientific publications."
  - Leter to Peter S. DuPonceau, December 10, 1841; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Amies, William
    Philadelphia, 1p. and address. A.L.S. Offers to the A.P.S.: painting "emblematic of the Union of our States." FILM 235 FRAME 11
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 11, 1841; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Forwards a box of pamphlets from Calcutta for the A.P.S., Which had been held in the Boston custom house.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, December 11, 1841; 8 1/4" x 10 3/8"; Ingersoll, Joseph Reed, 1786-1868
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Webster, secretary of state, has directed that a facsimilie of the Declaration of Independence be furnished the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 15, 1841; 7 3/8" x 9"; Bailey, Samuel, 1791-1870
    Sheffield, Yorkshire, England, 1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. L. Presents copy of his treatise on Berkeley's theory of vision to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Robert M.] Patterson, December 15, 1841; 7 1/2" x 9 3/16"; Breck, Samuel, 1771-1862
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsements. Requests Mr. Patterson or Mr. Kane to submit information regarding $2,500 deposited by the city with the A.P.S. for astronomical observatory.
  - Letter to Samuel Breck, December 16, 1841; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    Philadelphia, 5 pp. and endorsement. Dr.L.S. Account of observatory fund.
  - Account with the American philosophical society, Dec. 16, 1841; 13x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Report of committee on Nuttall's paper, Dec. 17, 1841; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    "Descriptions and notices of new and rare plants"; [Philadelphia] D.S.: Isaac Lea, Geo. B. Wood, and Jas. C. Booth. 1p. See APS Proc., II, 128. Printed: APS Trans., VIII, 251.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, December 17, 1841; 5" x 7 7/8"; Brown, Frederick
    U.S. Mint, [Philadelphia], Friday, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Respecting Mr. [Nathan] Dunn's lease of the museum room.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 18, 1841; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Cogswell, William, 1787-1850
    [Hanover, N.H.], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests the donation of publications of the A.P.S. for newly-founded Northern Academy of Arts and Sciences.
  - Letter to Samuel Breck, December 18, 1841; 8" x 10 1/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, 6 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Account of observatory fund.
  - Resolution adopted, December 23, 1841; 7 1/2" x 9 3/16"; Philadelphia (Pa.). City Council
    [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsements. D.S.: Levi Hollingsworth. Copy. Request that A.P.S. repay $2,500 to city treasury, originally granted for erection of observatory.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, Dec. 23, 1841; 9x7-1/4; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    L.S.: W. A. Graham. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 28, 1841; 8" x 10"; Force, Peter, 1790-1868
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: a box containing three volumes of the American Archives.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 31, 1841; 8" x 9 3/4"; Walker, Charles J.
    London, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. The London Electrical Society presents to the A.P.S.: Proceedings, part iii.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, 1841; 5" x 7 7/8"; Mitchell, John Kearsley, 1793-1858
    ----, ----, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.I. Suggests that notice regarding experiments on the subject of Dr. S. Brown's paper be deferred to a future time.
  - List of books needed to complete sets of journals, 1841; 8-3/4x7-3/4; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    [ca.]. A.D. 1p.
  - Charges on Ewing's hydrant from 1827 to 1841, American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to [Robert M.] Patterson, January 3, 1842; 7 1/2" x 9 3/12"; Breck, Samuel, 1771-1862
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Regarding reimbursement of $2,500 to the city treasury by the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Robley] Dunglison, January 6, 1842; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Encloses a letter handed to him at a meeting of the council of the Historical Society, found among the papers of the late John Vaughan.
  - Report of committee on paper by W. B. Rogers and H.D. Rogers on the geology of upper Canada and western Ohio, Jan. 7, 1842; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Isaac Lea and Rich[ar]d C. Taylor. 1p., end. See APS Proc., II, 137. Printed: APS Trans., VIII, 273ff.
  - Letter to Rob[er]t M. Patterson, January 7, 1842; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Hollinshead, Benjamin M.
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The Horticultural Society wishes to cancel lease of part of A.P.S. hall before same is sold to the city.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, January 7, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends copy of will of Mr. John Vaughan. Is separating Mr. Vaughan's personal papers from those belonging to A.P.S.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, January 10, 1842; 7 3/8" x 9"; Tidyman, Philip
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Charleston, 1 p., address and endorsement. Presents to the A.P.S.: four volumes of Statutes of South carolina.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Jan. 12, 1842; 9-1/2x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jul[ia]n R. Jackson. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, January 13, 1842; 8" x 10"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Richards and Mr. Patterson will be unable to attend meeting of the committee this morning. Have agreed upon a course to be proposed to Mr. Wharton.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Jan. 15, 1842; 10x7-3/4; National Institute for the Promotion of the Sciences
    Washington, A.L.S.: Francis Markoe, Jr. 1p.,end.and add. Concerning publications of the institute. Refers to A.D.Bache.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 20, 1842; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm. J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: P.Vaughan, Esqr. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 20, 1842; 10x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the secretaries of A.P.S., January 21, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S. "the copy owned by the late Mr. Vaughan of Chantrey's bust of William Vaughan of London, his Brother."
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., January 22, 1842; 7 1/4" X 8 7/8"; Graham, W. A.
    [London], 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. The Society of Arts returns thanks for A.P.S. Proceedings, no. 19.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, Jan. 22, 1842; 13x8; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edmund R. Daniell. 1p.,end. Thanks for APS "Journal".
  - Letter to George Ord, January 31, 1842; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of note of 28th. "I shall be very proud to have the agency of the Philosophical Society in Philadelphia."
  - Letter to George Ord, February 2, 1842; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Wylie, Samuel B. (Samuel Brown), 1773-1852
    Bellevue, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Apology for delinquency in payment of his dues to the A.P.S.
  - Account with [David Bailie] Warden, Feb. 3, 1842; 5-1/2x8; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, D.S.: J. J. Ledoren. 1p.and end. In French. Duplicate. Purchases for the society.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, February 3, 1842; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses a pamplet for the A. P. S. "Postages heretofore paid by me will be included in my a/c against the Socy."
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Mexico, February 4, 1842; 5 1/4" x 8 1/8"; Río, Andrés Manuel del, 1764-1849
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings for 1840-41. Regarding deposit of his memoir on the mineral chamelion with the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the secretaries of A.P.S., February 4, 1842; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has advised Mr. Ord that packages from the Geographical Society and the Zoölogical Society are at the custom house.
  - Letter to the secretaries of A.P.S., February 4, 1842; 7 7/8" x 10"; Snider, Jacob
    jr., to American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, 3 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. "... is prepared to execute to the American Philosophical Society, as far as practicable, the Trust confided to him by the will of the late Mr. John Vaughan."
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, February 4, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Notice of package for Society, directed to the care of John Vaughan, held at the custom house.
  - British Association for the Advancement of Science to Secretary of the A.P.S., February 12, 1842; 8 1/8" x 9 3/4"; British Association for the Advancement of Science
    London, 1p., address and endorsement. Announcement of twelfth annual meeting of B.A.A.S. to be held at Manchester in June.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 14, 1842; 4" x 4 5/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    ----, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Theodore Wylie, who wishes "to examine a recent number of the Bulletin of the French Institute."
  - Letter to Samuel B. Wylie, Hall of the A.P.S., February 14, 1842; 6" x 7 3/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.I. Acceptance of explanation by Dr. Wylie of causes of delinquency in payment of his dues to the A.P.S.
  - Statement of investments turned over to C[lement] C. Biddle, Feb. 15, 1842; 10x8; Ord, George, 1781-1866
  - Letter to P[eter] S. DuPonceau, February 15, 1842; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Ramage, Adam, 1771 or 2-1850
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Offers to put Dr. [Benjamin] Franklin's printing press in proper order at his own expense. See Pro., II, 148. FILM54-61 FRAME140
  - Letter to George Ord, February 15, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Snider, Jacob
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests bill for amount due by the Rev. William H. Furness to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, February 17, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Penington, John, 1799-1867
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Invitation to attend discourse by Job R. Tyson, at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, on Monday the 21st.
  - Valuation of the furniture left by John Vaughan and offered for sale to the American philosophical society, Feb. 23, 1842; Warren, William
    D.S. 3 items pertaining to this sale. Various sizes. Cf. Minutes, Feb. 18, 1842.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, February 24, 1842; 5" x 7 3/4"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has Marsden's Numismata Orientalia from A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the Secretary of A.P.S., February 24, 1842; 7 3/8" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Forwards parcels from Royal Society and Royal Geographical Society.
  - Letter to John Penington, February 25, 1842; 4" x 5 1/8"; Desmond, Daniel J., d. 1849
    ----, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding books belonging to A.P.S. loaned to him by the late John Vaughan.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 25, 1842; 7" x 8 15/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Statement of his accounts with the late John Vaughan. Acknowledges letters from Mr. DuPonceau. Congratulates Mr. Ord on his appointment as librarian of A.P.S.
  - Letter to [George] Ord, [Philadelphia], March 2, 1842; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; Bond, Henry, 1790-1859
    1 p. and endorsement. The secretary of the College of Physicians states the terms of annual rental of rooms for meetings.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, March 2, 1842; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of A.P.S., Fenchurch Street, [London], 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges resolutions condolence passed by the A.P.S. upon the death of his brother.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society, March 3, 1842; 5-1/2x8; Elliott, Isaac
    A.D.S. 1p.,end.by G.Ord,and end. This was not paid, but donated by Elliott, cf. Minutes, April 15, 1842.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 3, 1842; 7 5/16" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Arrangements as to European business of A.P.S since the death of John Vaughan. Thinks new corn law will operate favorably to the United States.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, March 3, 1842; 8 3/8" x 10 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp. L.S. Duplicate. Arrangements as to European business of A.P.S. since the death of John Vaughan. Thinks new corn law will operate favorably to the United States.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, March 3, 1842; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 3 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Details as to distribution of books sent per British Queen.
  - Report of committee on the Hall to which was referred the letter from Mr. Snyder relating to the bequest of Mr. Vaughan, March 4, 1842; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Geo[rge] Campbell. 2p., end. See APS Proc., II, 151.
  - Report of committee to which were referred the additional papers communicated by Mr. Simeon Borden, March 4, 1842; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Sears C. Walker and R. M. Patterson. 1p., end. See APS Proc., II, 149-150. Printed: APS Trans., IX, 33 ff.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 5, 1842; 7 5/16" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsements. L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: two parcels from the Linnean Society of London.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, March 7, 1842; 4 15/16" x 7 15/16"; Walker, Sears Cook, 1805-1853
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that the facilities of the A.P.S. library be extended to Mr. Borden, superintendent of the Massachusetts survey.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, March 11, 1842; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Peter, William, 1788-1853
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. N. 1p. enclosure. The British consul encloses record of the death of Mr. William Baker.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 14, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    jr., to George Ord, Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp,. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Letter of inquiry as to part played by the late John Vaughan in obtaining subscriptions for, and printing of, DuPonceau's Chinese Essay.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 16, 1842; 5 15/16" x 7 7/8"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has left casts of new fossil genus of quadrupeds near hall door of A.P.S.
  - List of books formerly the property of John Vaughan, having been part of his Library prior to 1798, now in the possession and belonging to J.Snider, Jr., March 17, 1842; 12-1/2x8; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 10p. (bound in APS. Donations Book, Vol.II, see date of April 1, 1842.) Not found May, 2011.
  - Statement and receipt to the American philosophical society for framing the Declaration of Independence, March 18, 1842; 3x7-1/2; Boyer, John
    D.S. 2p.attest.: Franklin Bache and P.S. DuPonceau,end.by George Ord.,and end.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, March 18, 1842; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Snider, Jacob
    jr., to John K. Kane, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests thta Mr. Kane present a number of books, "lately Mr. Vaughan's," to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, March 23, 1842; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Snider, Jacob
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding books and pamphlets, formerly belonging to Mr. Vaughan, to be given the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, March 23, 1842; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Snider, Jacob
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Sends Catalogue of Dr. Williams Library to the A.P.S., the same to be presented in the name of Mr. Petty Vaughan.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, March 26, 1842; 5" x 8"; Snider, Jacob
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Ord to deliver a copy of [Samuel] Kidd's China to Mr. DuPonceau.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 28, 1842; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gummere, John, 1784-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., 1p., West Haverford, address and endorsement. A.L.S. Paid Mr. Vaughan $11.09 for set of the Astronomische Nachrichten, and $5.00 dues for A.P.S on December 17, 1841.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 29, 1842; 5" x 8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding proper procedure in calling a meeting of the historical and literary committee.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 29, 1842; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Laments "the loss that Society and our family has sustained by the death of" John Vaughan. Congratulates Mr. Ord upon appointment as his successor.
  - Letter to George Ord, March 30, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    jr., to George Ord, [Philadelphia], 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Explains the terms of his recent donations of books to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 31, 1842; 4 15/16" x 7"; Walker, Charles J.
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: London Electrical Society, Proceedings, part iv.
  - Letter to George Ord, March, 1842; 7 3/8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    --, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Has "looked in vain" for original list of subscriptions to the Chinese work, but encloses copy of the same.
  - Letter to George Ord, L-7, April 1, 1842; 5" x 7 7/8"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement, A.N.S. Requests Mr. Ord to meet the committee on purchase and sale at 4.30 this afternoon.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, April 1, 1842; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Snider, Jacob
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests historical and literary committee to submit evidence relative to the expenses of printing Mr. DuPonceau's essay on the Chinese language.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 6, 1842; 10x8; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.S.Dixwell. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 6, 1842; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Treasurer of A.P.S., London, 1 p., L.S. Has forwarded three volumes of Transactions of British Association [for the Advancement of Science] to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 11, 1842; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.by A.D.B[ache] and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 12, 1842; 10x8; Lyceum of Natural History (New York, N. Y.)